Russell Hart

I am a web developer that is driven to create responsive web applications that meet customer needs. I enjoy learning new technologies and creating readable and efficient code.

My technical skills are supplemented by my engineering and mathematics degrees as well as my experience teaching engineering fundamentals to high school students. I also have extensive customer service experience from guiding with Nantahala Outdoor Center for many years.

in Portfolio

Web Developer Mountain Rest, SC russellbot@gmail.com

Work Experience

Web Developer, 2020 - present

Managed design tasks and handled all phases of app development. Reviewed and tested customer-facing prototypes before deployment. Improved performance of web applications using code splitting, caching, load balancing, and more. Projects include:

EZ-Shop E-commerce Mobile App

Full stack MERN project. The front end of this online store was built with the React-Native framework along with Redux for state management. The React Context API was used to manage authorization tokens and admin access. The back end was built using Node, Express, MongoDB, and Mongoose. Simple JWT were used for authentication. Users with Administrator access have full CRUD functionality through the app.

Cogito App

A single page application similar to Quora.com where users may post questions, answer questions, and upvote answers. The front end was built using Vue.js framework and the backend was built with Django REST framework. Users have full CRUD functionality for questions and answers that they have created, and they may like and unlike answers posted by other members of the site.

RSTY Clothing E-commerce Web App

This clothing website was built with React framework along with Redux for state management and Redux Saga to make asynchronous API calls. The back end uses a simple server built with Node and Express to access the Stripe API and process payments. The shop data is stored in Google Firestore and user authentication was established using Firebase.

Nantahala Outdoor Center, Head Guide, Apr 2004 - Present

Guided whitewater rafts and led oral discussions of natural and historical features on the Chattooga River, a National Wild and Scenic River. As head guide, responsible for training all newly hired guides to navigate the river and interact with guests.

Spring Valley High School, Pre-Engineering Teacher, Jul 2012 - Jul 2013

Taught Pre-Engineering classes as part of the Project Lead the Way curriculum. Developed lessons for Introduction to Engineering, Pre - Engineering, and Digital Electronics classes for students in grades 9-12. Sponsored and mentored the school's VEX robotics team.

Education

- University of South Carolina, Master of Arts in Teaching Mathematics, 2011 2012
- Clemson University, BS Biosystems Engineering, 2003 2007

Technical Skills

Programming language: JavaScript, Python, TypeScript

Frontend: React, React-Native, Vue.js, Redux, Redux-Saga, HTML, CSS/SASS

Backend: Node.js, Express.js, Django, Flask, GraphQL

Database: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis Cloud service: AWS Lambda, Firebase, Heroku Development Platform: Docker, CircleCl, Git